A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Governance and Public Policy (GPP), Office Files of Michael Seltzer and Maria Buck FA545
Rockefeller Archive Center
Ford Foundation records, Governance and Public Policy (GPP), Office Files of Michael Seltzer and Maria Buck
1993-1996
Rockefeller Archive Center
Seltzer, Michael (1947)
Buck, Maria
Ford Foundation
FA545
0.76 Cubic Feet 2 letter document boxes
Scope and Contents
Community Foundations and Rainbow Research files.
Conditions Governing Access
Records are open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC. Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Scope and Contents
Primarily documents the Community Foundations Changing Communities Initiative.
Biographical / Historical
Maria Buck is a university administrator whose career has included positions in nonprofits and government in addition to higher education. From 1994 to 1996, she worked as a program assistant in the Ford Foundation's Governance and Public Policy Program (GPP).
Buck's post-Ford Foundation career has included positions as Assistant Commissioner in the New York City Department of Small Business Services from 2002 to 2005 and as Executive Director for the Center for Career Pathways Institute at Medgar Evers College of the City University of New York from 2005 to 2007. For a number of years, she operated her own consulting firm, M.L. Buck and Associates, and in 2011, she became the University Coordinator for the Office of Academic Affairs at the City University of New York. She was then made CUNY University Director in 2013.
Buck earned a B.A. in sociology from the University of Connecticut in 1992 and a M.P.P. from the University of Michigan in 1994.
Biographical / Historical
Michael Seltzer is a consultant and educator in the nonprofit sector. From 1995 to 1998, he worked as a Program Officer at the Ford Foundation. He initially joined the Foundation as a Program Officer in the Governance and Public Policy Program (GPP). Following a change in the Foundation's program structure, Seltzer was moved into the Peace and Social Justice Program (PSJ) Governance and Civil Society unit (GCS). During his time at the Foundation, he was responsible for grantmaking to support organized philanthropy throughout the world.
After leaving the Ford Foundation in 1998, Seltzer became the Director of Business Enterprises for Sustainable Travel (BEST). Since 2007, he has lectured at Baruch College on philanthropy centered topics.
Seltzer earned a B.A. in international relations from Syracuse University in 1968. Prior to joining the Ford Foundation, he had consultant positions at Amnesty International and the TCC Group. He was also a co-founder and Executive Director of Funders Concerned about AIDS.
- Community Foundations -- Changing Communities Initiative -- Workshops and Updates, 1994 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations -- Continuation Guidelines Re: Continuing CF Initiative, 1995 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations -- Inclusive Practice Project, Council on Foundations, 1994 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations -- Memoranda, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations -- 5th Workshop -- Evaluations, 1996 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Workshop Materials and Annual Report Synopsis, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Proposals Request Form, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Planning -- Contacts/Address Listing, 1995 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- 26 Grantees -- Two Years Beginning 10/1/1993, 1995 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Arizona Community Foundation, Inc., 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Boston Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- California Community Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Dade Community Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Fairfield County Community Foundation, Inc., 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Hawaii Community Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Greater Kansas City Community Foundation and Affiliated Trusts, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- The Community Foundation of Greater Lorain County, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Madison Community Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Community Foundation of Greater Memphis, Inc., 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Community Foundation for Southeastern Michigan, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Minneapolis Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Central Minnesota Community Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Community Foundation of New Jersey, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Greater New Orleans Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Central New York Community Foundation, Inc., 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Community Foundation for Palm Beach and Martin Counties, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Philadelphia Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Rochester Area Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Rockford Community Trust, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- San Francisco Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Saint Paul Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- St. Louis Community Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Trident Community Foundation, 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Tucson Community Foundation, Inc., 1993 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Greater Worcester Community Foundation, Inc., 1993 (Box 1)
- Non-Profit Sector -- New Leadership, 1995; n.d. (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities, Diverse Needs -- Rainbow Research, 1993-1996 (Box 1)
- Community Foundations: Changing Communities -- Diverse Needs (Box 2)